Guide to the Victor S. Navasky Papers TAM.594
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VI: Political Cartoons and The Art of Controversy, 1910-2013
  - Subseries VIA: Research and Related Materials
    - Articles: "War in the Funnypapers: Cooperation Between the Federal Government and the Comic Book Industry, 1940-1945" by Paul Hirsch, 2009 (Box 58, Folder 25)
    - Articles: "Whose Art is it Anyway", 1992 (Box 58, Folder 26)
    - Auth, Tony, undated (Box 58, Folder 27)
    - Baudrillard, Jean, 1988 (Box 58, Folder 28)
    - Beerbohm, Max, 2012 (Box 58, Folder 29)
    - Bell, Steve, 2002-2011, undated (Box 58, Folder 30)
    - Berger, John: Navasky notes on Ways of Seeing, undated (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - Bibliography (few entries), 2008, 2009, undated (Box 58, Folder 32)
    - Billy Ireland Cartoon Library and Museum, 2011 (Box 58, Folder 33)
    - Blitt, Barry (includes The New Yorker "Politics of Fear" cover controversy), 1993-1994, 2008 (Box 58, Folder 34)
    - The Brain: Articles, 1993-2001, undated (Box 58, Folder 35)
    - The Brain: Articles, 2005-2009 (Box 58, Folder 36)
    - The Brain: Articles, 2011-2012 (Box 58, Folder 37)
    - The Brain: Eye, Brain and Vision by David Hubel, undated (Box 58, Folder 38-39)
    - The Brain: Freud, 1996-2008 (Box 58, Folder 40)
    - Brodner, Steve, 2004 (Box 58, Folder 41)
    - Brown, Dave and David G. Brown, 2011 (Box 58, Folder 42)
    - Bryant, Mark, 2006-2010 (Box 58, Folder 43)
    - Bulgarian Cartoons, 2006, 2011 (Box 58, Folder 44)
    - Caricature, 1938, 1983, 2008-2011 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Caricature, 2005, 2011, 2012 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Caricature: Baudelaire, 2010 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Caricature: Caricature, 1940 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Caricature: Chinese-"The Fuming Image: Cartoons and Public Opinion in Late Republican China, 1945-1949", 2010 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Caricature: Ethnic-"'I Want a Real Coon': Mark Twain and Late-Nineteenth Century Ethnic Caricature" by Henry B. Wonham, 2000 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Caricature: "Four Modes of Caricature: Reflections Upon a Genre", undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Caricature: "George Townshend Revisited: The Politican as Caricaturist" by Herbert M. Atherton, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Caricature: Indian-"Freedom to Cartoon, Freedom to Speak" by R.K. Laxman, 1989 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Caricature: "Infinite Jest: Caricature and Satire From Leonardo to Levine" (Exhibit at the Met), 2011 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Caricature: "The (Neuro)-Aesthetics of Caricature: Representations of Reality in Bret Easton Ellis' Lunar Park" by Timothy C. Baker, 2009 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Caricature: "On a Theory of Political Caricature", May 15, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Caricature: Photojournalism and Caricature, 2000, 2010 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Caricature: Psychology of Caricature, 1992, 1996 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Caricature: Themes, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Carrier, David, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Cartoonist rights, 2011-2012 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Cartoonist Rights Network International (CRNI), 2006-2011 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - "Cartoonists Speak Out...The Pen is Mightier Than the Sorehead" (The Nation), Jan 17, 1994 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Churchill, Winston: in Nazi propaganda, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Cinderella Press Ltd. envelope with cartoon image, May 21, 2012 (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Comic Books: "Overview" by James McWilliams (First Amendment Center), 2003 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - Conrad, Paul, 1999-2011 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Cruikshank, George, 2000, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Danish Cartoons: Charlie Hebdo Firebombing/Mohammed Cartoon, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Danish Cartoons: Controversy, 1985, 2005-2011 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Danish Cartoons: Controversy, 2006-2012 (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - Danish Cartoons: "The Danish Cartoon Affair: Free Speech, Racism, Islamism, and Integration", 2006 (Box 59, Folder 28)
    - Danish Cartoons: Jyllands-Posten, 2006-2011 (Box 59, Folder 29)
    - Danish Cartoons: "Muhammad Cartoons and Humor Research: A Collection of Essays", undated (Box 59, Folder 30)
    - Danish Cartoons: "The Muhammad Cartoons and Multicultural Democracies", 2009 (Box 59, Folder 31)
    - Danish Cartoons: "Religion and Freedom of Speech: Portraits of Muhammad", 2007 (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - Daumier, Honoré, 1992, undated (Box 59, Folder 33)
    - Delonas, Sean: New York Post chimp cartoon, 2003, 2009 (Box 59, Folder 34)
    - Delonas, Sean: Sharpton, Ferrer cartoon and the 2001 NYC Mayoral Race, 2001-2011 (Box 59, Folder 35)
    - Distribution, 1995, undated (Box 59, Folder 36)
    - Edwards, Robert, 1994-2011 (Box 59, Folder 37)
    - E-mail (research), 2008-2013 (Box 59, Folder 38)
    - Ferzat, Ali, Oct 2011-Nov 2011 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    - German Cartooning (portion of unidentified book), undated (Box 59, Folder 40)
    - Giles, Carl, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 41)
    - Gill, André, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 42)
    - Gillray, James, 2007, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 43)
    - Glaser, Milton, 2002 (Box 59, Folder 44)
    - Goldstein, Robert Justin, undated (Box 59, Folder 45)
    - Gombrich, Ernst, 2009, undated (Box 59, Folder 46)
    - Goya, Francisco, 1989, 2011, undated (Box 59, Folder 47)
    - Grossman, Robert (includes letters to The Nation re: Hillary Clinton), 2008 (Box 59, Folder 48)
    - Grosz, George, 2011 (Box 59, Folder 49)
    - Harrison, Ted: Interview and ...from the Ridiculous to the Sublime..., 2010, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Heartfield, John, 1991, 2010 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Heller, Steve, 2008, undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Hiley, Nicholas, 2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - History, 1977, 2009-2012, undated (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Hoffman, Werner, 1957, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Hogarth, William, 2000, 2001, 2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Humor Theory: Articles, 1974, 1981, 1988, 2005, undated (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Humor Theory: "De la divinagracia: Reflexiones en torno a la relacion entre humor y fe" (Student paper on the relationship between humor and faith-Andres Bello Catholic University-in Spanish), undated (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Hustler Magazine and Larry C. Flynt v. Jerry Falwell, 2008, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Illustration, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Impact, 1998-2011 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Impact: Power of Images, 2008, 2009, undated (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Iran newspaper cockroach cartoon controversy, undated (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Jackson, Raymond ("JAK"), 1997, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Johnson, Isabel: "Cartoons" from The Public Opinion Quarterly, vol 1, no 3 (Jul 1937), 2011 (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Kaiser, Wolf, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Kimmelman, Michael, 2006, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Koestler, Arthur (notes), undated (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Kohler, Wolfgang, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Kollwitz, Käthe, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Kraus, Jerelle, 2003, 2008, undated (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Latuff, Carlos, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 23)
    - Lawsuits, 1996, 2010, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 24)
    - Lehrer, Jonah, 2008, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 25)
    - Lepore, Ernie "Poetry, Medium and Message", 2011 (Box 60, Folder 26)
    - Levine, David, 1984, 2008, 2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 27)
    - Low, David: "David Low and the Sociology of Caricature" by Lawrence H. Streicher, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 28)
    - Low, David: Photocopies of Low cartoons from John Heartfield Archive at Akademie Der Kunste, 1939 (Box 60, Folder 29)
    - Low, David, 2002-2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 30)
    - Mankoff, Robert, 2009 (Box 60, Folder 31)
    - Marlette, Doug, 2004, undated (Box 60, Folder 32)
    - The Masses (includes photocopies of article fragments from 1914, 1915, plus descriptive materials), 2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 33)
    - McCabe (Thomas B. McCabe Memorial Lecture), 2009 (Box 60, Folder 34)
    - McLuhan, Marshall, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 35)
    - Memos, 2009-2012, undated (Box 60, Folder 36)
    - Minor, Robert, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 37)
    - Mitchell, W.J.T., 2005, 2006 (Box 60, Folder 38)
    - Naji, Al-Ali, 2004, 2010 (Box 60, Folder 39)
    - Nast, Thomas, 2001-2013, undated (Box 60, Folder 40)
    - Nast, Thomas: "Editorial Cartoonist Thomas Nast: Anti-Irish, Anti-Catholic bigot?" by Michael Dooley, 2012 (Box 60, Folder 41)
    - Nast, Thomas: "Thomas Nast and the Public School of the 1870s" by Benjamin Justice, 2005 (Box 60, Folder 42)
    - New Statesman (John Major Libel Suit), 1993, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 43)
    - The New Yorker Magazine: Covers rejected, 2012 (Box 60, Folder 44)
    - The New Yorker Magazine: "From Racism to Tokenism: The Changing Face of Blacks in The New Yorker Cartoons" by Ruth Thibodeau, 1989 (Box 60, Folder 45)
    - Nieman Reports: "Editorial Cartoons: The Impact and Issues of an Evoloving Craft" vol 58, no 4, Winter 2004 (Box 60, Folder 46)
    - Oesterheld, Hector German, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 47)
    - Oliphant, Pat, undated (Box 60, Folder 48)
    - Permissions, undated (Box 60, Folder 49)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1973, 2011, undated (Box 60, Folder 50)
    - Plantu, 2010, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 51)
    - Platt, Steve (New Statesman and John Major Story), 1993-2007, 2011 (Box 60, Folder 52)
    - Platt, Steve: "The Right to be Offensive: Poltical Cartoonists and Political Correctness", 1994 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - "Politics of Fear" New Yorker cover reaction, 2008 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Porterfield, Todd (on caricature), 2011 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Propaganda, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Raemaekers, Louis, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Research images, undated (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Resources, 2010 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Reviews and abstracts on related books, 1971, 1989, 2001-2012, undated (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Rhodes, Gillian, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Rowlandson, Thomas, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Sakurai, Heiko, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Scarfe, Gerald, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Schellmann, Hilke: Reasearch-Lists of books and articles concerning the brain and art/cartoons, undated (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Searle, Ronald, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Segal, Jon (Random House editor): Drafts, with annotations, of letter describing planned book, 2011, undated (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Sensation (article concerning Brooklyn Museum of Arts "Sensation" exhibit), 1999 (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - Sex-difference research, undated (Box 61, Folder 17)
    - Sociology of cartoons, 2002, undated (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Sorel, Edward, 1988, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Speeches, 2009, 2013, undated (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Spiegelman, Art, 1993-2011 (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Steadman, Ralph, 2000-2013 (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Sunenblick, Jesse: his article "Little Murders" (why editorial illustrations get killed and why it matters), 2004 (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Szyk, Arthur, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Timeline, 2008-2010, undated (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Trip: England/Germany (May 21-June 2, 2011) (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Visual culture, 2005, undated (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Visual language, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Walker, Martin: Selected pages from Daily Sketches-A Cartoon History of British Twentieth Century Politics, 1978 (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Waltzer, Ben: Research and comments, 2006, 2011-2012 (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Weil, Robert (W.W. Norton editor): Drafts of letter describing planned book, undated (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Westin, Alan: Selected pages from his book Getting Angry Six Days a Week: A Portfolio of Political Cartoons, 1979 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Wetzel, Juliane (anti-Semitism and images), circa 2008, 2011 (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Zuma, Jacob: Images (Brett Murray and Zapiro), 2003-2012 (Box 61, Folder 34)
  - Subseries VIB: The Writing Process
    The writing process subseries contains drafts, edits, reviewer comments, notes, and many illustrations, some in color. Within the folders of illustrations, there are numerous duplicates. There are also illustrations that did not appear in the final book. Of interest are the many changes Navasky made to the structure of the book during the writing process. It should be noted that some of the drafts are incomplete. (The working manuscripts reflect the use of Microsoft Word's change tracking feature.)
    - Draft (MS Word change tracking), 2011-2012 (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Draft, May 17, 2012 (Box 61, Folder 36-37)
    - Draft, Jun 1, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Draft, Jun 6, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Draft, Jul 18, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 3-4)
    - Draft (MS Word change tracking and Navasky annotations), Jul 18, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Draft, Jul 25, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Draft, Aug 1, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Draft (MS Word change tracking), Aug 9, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Draft (MS Word change tracking), Aug 28, 2012 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Draft, undated (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Draft: "Appendix, or Chapter Four, or Conclusion", undated (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Draft: Bibliography, undated (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Draft fragments, 2011 (Box 62, Folder 13-14)
    - Draft fragments, 2011-2012 (Box 63, Folder 1-2)
    - Draft fragments, undated (Box 63, Folder 3-11)
    - Draft: "The Gallery", undated (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Draft: "The Gallery" (few sections; many deletions identified), undated (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Draft: "The Gallery" sections (some include color illustrations), undated (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Draft with illustrations (heavily annotated), undated (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - Draft with illustrations (incorporates initial book proposal), undated (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Draft with illustrations (reviewer comments embedded), undated (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Draft with illustrations (some in color), undated (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Draft with illustrations (some in color), original, undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Draft with illustrations (photocopy), undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Drafts: Introductory Essay, undated (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Drafts: Timeline, undated (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Edits, inserts, comments by others, 2011, 2012, undated (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Edits, inserts, comments by others: Waltzer, Ben, 2012, 2013, undated (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Illustrations, undated (Box 64, Folder 9-10)
    - Illustrations (many in color), undated (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Notes, Jun 25, 2011 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Notes, undated (Box 64, Folder 13-14, Box 65, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes: rough essay, 2008, 2011 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Notes: rough exhibits, 2011 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Notes: Top 25 draft, 2011 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Post Publication, 2013 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Post Publication: Reviews, 2013 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Proposals (various versions and drafts), undated (Box 65, Folder 8-9)
- Series VII: Other Navasky Writings, 1930s-2012
  - Subseries VIIA: Books
    In 1976, Victor Navasky donated the bulk of his papers associated with the book, Kennedy Justice, to the John F. Kennedy Library. A copy of the deed of gift and an initial list of folder titles are included in this subseries. There also remain in this collection one complete draft with editors' annotations (1971), a set of proofs, several folders of research material, sections of the book that were printed in the New York Post, and numerous reviews.
    The subseries also includes material associated with two books Navasky co-authored with Christopher Cerf – The Experts Speak, The Definitive Compendium of Authoritative Misinformation and Mission Accomplished! Or How We Won the War in Iraq: The Experts Speak. Each book contains a compilation of quotes by "experts" who turned out to be completely wrong. In addition to contracts, reviews, notes, and other related materials, there are several annotated drafts of the Iraq edition.
    - The Experts Speak, 1981, 1993-1997 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - The Experts Speak: Contracts and royalties, 1981-1985, 1991-1993, 2001 (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - The Experts Speak: Design samples, edits, revisions and notes, 1982-1983 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - The Experts Speak: Publicity and reviews, 1984-1985, 1998 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition (Mission Accomplished! Or How We Won The War in Iraq: The Experts Speak), 2003, 2007-2008 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Draft of introduction, Nov 2, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Manuscript draft with annotations, Oct 21, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Manuscript draft with annotations, Nov 3, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Manuscript draft with annotations, Nov 4, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Manuscript insertions, Oct 26, 2007 (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - The Experts Speak: Iraq edition-Notes, undated (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - Kennedy Justice: Donation of papers to John F. Kennedy Library (includes deed of gift), 1973, 1981 (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - Kennedy Justice: Donation of papers to John F. Kennedy Library (includes folder title list), 1990, undated (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 1-132, 1971 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 132a-276, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 277-379, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 380-518, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 519-661, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 662-841, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) pp. 769-842, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Kennedy Justice: Draft (with editors' annotations) index, 1971 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Kennedy Justice: Notes and fragments, undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Kennedy Justice: Proofs (Box 67)
    - Kennedy Justice: Related Correspondence (includes letter from Bud Schulberg to Marvin Kitman re: RFK and Hoffa and letter accusing Navasky of misstatements re: James M. Landis case), 1971-2000 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Kennedy Justice: Research and related material, 1948, 1972, 1975, 2001 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Kennedy Justice: Research and related material-"Biographical Sketches of the Attorneys General", 1946 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Kennedy Justice: Research and related material-"The Performance of the FBI in Investigating Violations of Federal Laws Protecting the Right to Vote--1960-1967", 1971 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Kennedy Justice: Reviews, Oct 1971 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Kennedy Justice: Reviews, 1971, undated (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Kennedy Justice: Reviews, 1972 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Kennedy Justice: Sections printed in the New York Post, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - The Art of Making Magazines, 2002-2012 (Box 95)
    - Jack O'Dell Research and Drafts, 2001-2014 (Box 106, Box 107)
  - Subseries VIIB: Articles and Essays
    This subseries contains articles, essays, book reviews, letters to the editor, and similar writings by Victor Navasky, a representative sample of Navasky's output but, by no means, all of it. Research material, correspondence, drafts, notes, and other associated items are included with some of the articles. There are pieces from as early as 1958. Among the publications represented are the New York Times, New York Times Magazine, The Yale Law Journal, Esquire magazine, Atlantic Monthly, The Plain Dealer, and The Nation. Many of Navasky's "In Cold Print" columns from the New York Times Book Review are included. Articles written by Navasky also appear in other series, as appropriate.
    A Navasky article -- "Ronald Reagan and the Supremes" -- appeared in Esquire magazine's April 1987 issue. In addition to a copy of the piece, this subseries contains a great deal of associated research material, covering not only judicial appointments but many other aspects of Reagan's time in office.
    - Articles, 1968-1979 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Articles, 1982-2009, undated (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Articles: Article re: Foyle's Bookshop, London (Travel and Leisure) - includes background material, 1973, undated (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Articles: "Big Mike on Campus" (Esquire Sep 1988) - Navasky discusses the college days of Michael Dukakis (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Articles: "A CBS Documentary About a CBS Blacklist" (Navasky article on John Henry Faulk and the CBS program "Fear on Trial") - article, drafts, correspondence, background, 1975 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Articles: "A CBS Documentary About a CBS Blacklist" (Navasky article on John Henry Faulk and the CBS program "Fear on Trial") - notes and partial transcript of "Fear on Trial", undated (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - Articles: "The Demons of Salem, With Us Still" (New York Times Sep 8, 1996) - Navasky discusses film of Arthur Miller's The Crucible (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - Articles: "E.L. Doctorow: I Saw A Sign" (includes article drafts and notes from Doctorow interview), 1980 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - Articles: "E.L. Doctorow: I Saw A Sign" (includes draft of "How Writers Write" by Doctorow and interview by Random House staff), 1975, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - Articles: Early articles (includes correspondence with Frontier magazine), 1958-1959, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Articles: The Federal Trade Commission's Advertising Substantiation Program (article for MORE A Journalism Review) - drafts, fragments, notes, circa 1971-1972 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Articles: The Federal Trade Commission's Advertising Substantiation Program (article for MORE A Journalism Review) - related material, 1977-1984 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Articles: The Federal Trade Commission's Advertising Substantiation Program (article for MORE A Journalism Review) - research, 1971-1972, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Articles: "Levi Article" - material related to article on Edward H. Levi (article not included), 1975 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine, 1967-1971 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine, 1972-1977, 1996, 2012 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article (Iran), 1976 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article, notes, undated (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article (Iran) research, 1962-1977 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article (Iran) research (includes Mar 1976 "Profile on Iran"), 1974-1976 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article (Iran) research, Committee for Artistic and Intellectual Freedom in Iran, 1973-1976 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Articles: The New York Times Magazine - Boycott article (Iran) research, Index on Censorship and other materials, 1975-1976 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Articles: Op Ed on George (draft, notes, research), 1995, undated (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Articles: "The Oscar No One Will Win", 1999 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Articles: [Playboy] article on informers, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Articles: "Reunion at Watergate" (The Columbia Forum Fall 1973) - article, edited draft and background material (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Articles: "The Rights of Journalists" (The Nation Aug 2005), 2005-2010 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Articles: "The Rights of Journalists" - research articles, 2004-2005 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Articles: "The Rights of Journalists" - research articles, 2005 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Articles: "The Rights of Journalists" - research articles, news clippings, 2004-2005 (Box 68, Folder 19)